Hello and welcome to this first module of
our Talent and Careers' online learning journey.
During this video,
you will learn how to write a compelling CV
and you will familiarize with the IE CV template.
Your CV is a marketing document
that must be tailored
depending on the audience
you want it to direct it to.
Employers use the information in your CV
to determine how suitable you are for a position.
This means that you should customize
the information in your CV
to each position you apply for.
This is the IE CV template.
We will go through the different sections
for you to see what information
you should include in each one.
This template has been created
with the input of recruiters and alumni
from different sectors and locations
and you may have to do some small modifications
depending on the sector or the country
you are applying to.
It is a live document
that changes with recruitment trends.
Under your name, you should include
your contact information and work permits.
You should also add your LinkedIn URL,
but make sure you have shortened it before.
You will learn how to do this
on the LinkedIn module.
The first section in your CV
is your professional summary.
The professional summary
should be short and sweet.
Catch by the reader's attention,
point out information
that is highly relevant to the role
and help out the candidate
stand out from the rest.
So no overused common phrases
and generic skills.
For the most senior profiles,
this is the space to express
what you have to offer a prospective employer,
not to express aspirations.
For more junior profiles,
you can include information
on your educational background,
your main roles, functions
and areas of specialization,
the sectors in which you have developed
your professional experience,
your most relevant skills
and your sector and function of interest.
The second section, education,
is where you include
your academic accomplishments
starting with the most recent.
In no more than three bullet points,
you can list your most significant results,
such as a high GPA,
your most relevant courses
or any other relevant
extracurricular activities
that may increase the chances of getting a role.
Here is where understanding your industry
requirements plays an important role.
The professional experience section
should include any internships
and previous relevant work experience.
State your job title,
primary tasks and responsibilities
using the action verb + task + result format.
We will look further into how
to write winning bullet points in another video.
You can also include relevant information
about the company you worked for
such as the sector, their revenue,
the number of employees
or even their web page.
Languages, technical skills
and volunteering experiences are also key.
If these are very relevant
for the role that you're applying to
or something that you feel
will differentiate you from other candidates,
make sure you create a separate section for them.
Studies show that recruiters
spend less than 10 seconds deciding
if they want to continue reading your CV or not.
Make sure you make it easy to read,
keep a consistent format
and stand out the most important information.
Of course, no typos
or grammar mistakes are allowed.
So, are you ready to start writing your CV?
Don't forget to check out our CV writing guide
for further information.