Welcome back.
During this video,
we will learn about
applicants tracking systems
and how to optimize our CVs
to make sure they reach
recruiters and hiring managers sites.
As you may know,
applicant tracking systems are software
that simplify
the recruitment processes for companies
by ranking the applicants they receive
based on the information
that appears in their CVs.
Applicant tracking systems collect
information of all the applicants to a job
and compare them
based mainly on the keywords
that the candidates include in their CV.
These keywords could reflect
technical skills, competencies
or the knowledge of software
amongst many others.
They will rank all the applicants
based on the keywords
and provide the recruiters
and hiring managers with a list
of the most suitable candidates.
Most top employers use this type of system
to simplify and speed up
their recruitment processes
as they usually screen out around
70% of the resumes they receive
for each position that get posted.
This is either because their experience
does not reflect the desired qualifications
or because they are submitted in formats
that are illegible for the system.
Making sure that we use the correct keywords
and we submit our CVs in an adequate format
can increase our chances
of moving past this initial screening process.
Throughout this online program,
we have already mentioned the importance
of tailoring our CV to each job we apply to.
Make sure your CV includes keywords
relevant to the job you're applying for.
These keywords will be available
not only in the job description,
but also in the company web page,
where you might be able
to find further information
on what an ideal candidate
would look like for that company.
Most relevant keywords
can be used more than once
since the system will give you points
for every time these keywords
appear on your resume.
But make sure you don't overuse them,
up to a level in which they stop making sense.
Make sure you start preparing
and identifying the most relevant keywords
for your target sector and role
as soon as possible.
Project management for consulting
or financial modeling for finance
are just a couple of examples,
but these keywords will change
depending on the sector
and even some time on the companies.
Companies with
very strong corporate culture can even
have keywords of their own.
Including sector specific keywords
in your CV could be difficult
if you don't have
any professional experience in that sector.
But good news,
you can use your professional summary
to include the keywords
that are relevant for the role,
but may be difficult to incorporate
within your educational
or professional experience sections.
Include the date in your work experience
and education sections.
The system might try to filter
by the years of experience
or your graduation date by reading these.
Make sure you use both acronyms
and the long format version of keywords.
For example,
MBA and Master in Business Administration
or MIM and Master In Management.
ATS like simple formats with traditional fonts.
It is easier for them to read
through this type of CVs.
So, avoid using tables,
columns or fancy graphics.
Make sure you use
standard resume section headlines,
such as education or professional experience,
to make it easier for the system to identify them
and submit your CV in a .docx format when possible.
As you can see, optimizing your CV
through this first online screening process
requires planning and time.
There are lots of online resources out there
that will help you prepare to beat ATS.
Make sure you check them out
in the same section.