Setting up your LinkedIn profile is easy
and you want to make it smart too,
so it reflects your professional goals.
Our experience has taught us this is key
considering how international
and diverse we are in the IE community.
Here are four insider tips:
you want to set up a location for your profile,
set up a language for your profile,
set up a personal LinkedIn URL,
set up your visibility.
Set up a location for your profile.
When you're setting a location
for your profile,
think about where your potential employers
or investors will be.
That is the location you want to have
on your LinkedIn profile.
Right now, you're studying your degree
in Spain.
It is possible that some of you
may want to stay in Spain for work,
others may want to go back to their home country
upon graduation
and yet others may want to work
at an international hub
in a different country altogether.
The location setting lets
prospective employers or investors
know where you wish to keep developing
your professional career.
If you are unsure as to what geography
you want to target,
that's okay.
It may be even too early in the program
for you to decide.
You can just have Spain in your location
and state that you will be open to relocate
in your professional summary.
Set up a language for your profile.
When you're setting up the language for your profile,
go back to the earlier reflection
on which geography
you want to target after graduation.
Whatever language people speak there
will be the language for your profile.
In some countries,
English is the native language
or the language preferred for business.
In other countries,
there may be a different,
more dominant language for business
that is not English.
So, some of you may need to have
just the one profile in this language,
in English,
while others may need to have two,
one in English, which is more or less standard,
and the other one in Spanish or Dutch,
whatever language potential employers
and investors are going to be fluent in.
Set up a personal LinkedIn URL.
When we're thinking about establishing
an online presence,
we need to consider
the online environment itself.
In it, URLs are very meaningful
to understand the content
to which they're taking us.
This is the case of your profile's URL.
The URL automatically assigned to you
by LinkedIn
will look something like this.
You have the LinkedIn handle
followed by your name
with dashes
and a somewhat long series of numbers.
Be aware that it can
and should be personalized
just to show your name with a spelling
and style of your choosing.
You will be pasting this URL into your CV
and potentially it will be shared amongst
prospective employers or investors.
Personalizing your LinkedIn URL is easy.
Just go to your profile
on the upper right-hand corner
and change it.
Set up your visibility.
Decide what and when you want to share.
LinkedIn is all about sharing,
but at this point in time,
you will be working on your profile
and making many changes, big and small.
So, you do not want your network
to be notified every time, right?
Remember to switch off sharing profile changes
with your network.
It is an automatic function on LinkedIn
that works well
when you change your job title, for example,
as it would let everybody know
that you just got a promotion
- hurray! -
but it will not bode well for you
if you're in the initial stages
of setting up your profile
or just making it better.
You can do this in the settings
and privacy tab in your profile.
The same goes
for your overall profile visibility.
Keep it less restrictive
when you're looking for a professional change
or more restricted if you're not open
to new professional opportunities,
so you will not appear in recruiter searches.
This you can manage as well
in the settings and privacy.