With 20 million plus open job listings
at any given time
and 30 million plus companies,
the abundance of information on LinkedIn
is incredible.
It gives you the opportunity
to learn about your market.
You can identify trends,
like sought-after roles
and growing companies,
or even see how one role varies
from one company to another.
Understanding what is needed out there
will help you leverage your profile
and play on your strengths.
The numbers will definitely add up for you
if you use the data in the framework
of a structured search strategy.
Let's see how you can use LinkedIn
as a tool in your search strategy.
You may define your target companies,
cultivate your network
and find and apply for jobs.
Defining your target companies.
Find out which companies
are the best fit for you
and list them.
You can research by sector, by role
and even by alumni working there.
This is actually a good indicator
that they value talent coming from IE.
You may be tempted
to let yourself get carried away
by the trends in your program.
But there are many great companies out there
that can be a really good fit for you
and your future career.
Find out more about them
by following them on LinkedIn
and keeping up to date with their news.
Cultivate key contacts in each company.
If you network from the beginning of the program
and follow relevant
sector-related professionals,
chances are that you may get referred by them
for a job when it opens up.
The networking being done on LinkedIn,
the one that really thrives
is informational networking,
the kind that is driven by sharing of content
and professional opinion,
not so much the one that asks
for job referrals from the get go.
You can learn more about networking
with these prospective employers
in the earlier section,
"Build your network".
So, form a well-established network
of professionals
that you can tap into later for jobs.
Note the word, later on.
Find jobs and apply.
When you're ready to start applying,
you will see an entire section
dedicated to this on the topmost menu.
Search for relevant jobs by title,
skill or company
and then by location.
Do remember to set up job alerts
and manage them according to preferences.
If you are targeting jobs by company only,
you may also set up an alert
within the company page.
Once you enter your keywords for the search,
you can browse for jobs using combinations
of all the filters at the top;
by sort, by company, by date,
by LinkedIn features
- more about this later -
and by experience required.
When applying,
you will find two types of button,
both blue
and fairly visible to the name of the job:
Apply and Easy Apply.
What is the difference between the two?
The Apply button will automatically
redirect you to the company website.
Once there, you will go through
the company's own process of application
through their platform
or applicant tracking system, ATS.
The Easy Apply button,
on the other hand,
will allow you to apply directly to the job
with your LinkedIn profile
within LinkedIn as the platform.
My advice would be to try and avoid
the Easy Apply button
in favor of the Apply.
Easy Apply is indeed easy
and it takes little time,
but most companies manage candidates
from their own platform.
It gives them much more traceability
and wealth of information on your profile.
Clicking the Apply button
and thus going through the company website
will bode well for you.
You will have the possibility to include
information tailored to the company
and additional documents,
such as a cover letter.
You will even be able to get
an official referral for your application
from someone from within the company.
If LinkedIn is the go-to source
for job listings globally,
it is very likely
competition will be quite intense.
So your edge,
what will make you stand out
from the competition,
will come from how effectively
you leverage your network.
The more time you invest
building your network
and your credibility on LinkedIn,
the more likely you are to have a unique insight
into the job of your dreams
and possibly a referral for it.