Why Now? We live in an era
of data abundance.
Thousands of sensors around us
are producing vast amounts of data,
which can serve as training sets
for machine learning algorithms
and make them improve their performance faster.
Furthermore, the infrastructure
required to program and run
the machine learning algorithms
is becoming cheaper and largely available.
For example, cloud services can help running
large scale machine learning algorithms,
reducing costs and
prohibiting resource requirements.
Finally, the processing capabilities
required to run
large-scale machine learning
are improving substantially.
Typical examples are graphic processing
units – or GPUs – that operate
much faster than our normal CPUs
in our computers,
speeding up the calculations required
by machine learning algorithms.
All this, namely
data storage and processing capabilities open
new (existing) paths for machine learning.