I am Konstantina Valogianni,
a professor at IE Business School,
and I'm going to introduce you
today to what machine learning is.
According to Tom Mitchell,
Professor of Machine Learning
at Carnegie Mellon University
and one of the firsts to create
a comprehensive definition of machine learning,
a computer program
is said to learn from experience,
with respect to some tasks
and a certain performance measure,
if its performance of these tasks
improves with experience.
In other words, it is the science
of teaching a computer algorithm
to collect feedback
from previous performances
so that it improves its performance over time
with respect to a predefined objective.
For example,
a computer that learns to play checkers
might improve its performance
as measured by its ability to win
at playing checkers
by playing games against itself.
There are numerous examples
of using machine learning in business.
For example,
Amazon's recommendations are based
on learning from a user's previous preferences;
or Facebook is now able to use
face recognition to identify faces in pictures
using machine learning trained on past data.
And those are just a couple of them.