Hello.
During this short video,
you will learn how to create bullet points
in order to show
your greatest accomplishments in your CV.
I will show you how to create your bullet points
focusing on your achievements
instead of the tasks you performed.
To be able to do this,
we are always going to follow
the following structure:
action verb + task + result.
Let's take a look at
these two versions of one same CV.
This person is talking about
one same professional experience,
but the way that he focuses
on his achievements on the improved version
of his resume allows the recruiter
to really understand the impact
he had within his company and how much value
he really created for his customers.
You must always start your bullet points
with an action verb in the past.
Let's take a look at this example here.
We have "directed", "developed",
"empowered", "applied" and "recommended".
We can see that these action verbs
are already making your achievements
look a lot more powerful.
The next step would be your tasks.
In this case, it would be
"diverse teams of up to 18 people",
"re-branding strategy and comprehensive
integrated marketing communications plan",
"through training/education,
presentations and consultations
on due diligence and thorough risk assessment",
"framework to several Southeast Asian markets
by conducting in-depth
primary and secondary research",
"manufacturer to move suppliers
from India to China".
The last step to have our bullet points
correctly formulated would be
to talk about the results.
Let's take a look again at the example.
The results shown
in these bullet points would be
"to successfully achieve annual objectives",
"to strengthen market position
and regional expansion
through value-add differentiation",
"to devise improved
business/marketing strategies",
"to make spot-on recommendations regarding
market potential, legalities and entry timelines"
and "lowering manufacturing cost by 20%".
Another important thing
that you should include
when drafting your bullet points
is quantitative information.
This helps the recruiters and hiring managers
really understand the impact of your actions.
"Teams of up to 18 people" or "reducing cost by 20%"
are two great examples
of quantitative information
you can include in your resumes.
As you can see, in all of our examples,
we have followed the same structure:
action verb + task + result,
adding quantitative information
whenever it's possible.
Please take a look at the CV writing guide
to see further examples
and to access a list of action verbs
that can get you started
writing amazing bullet points.