Hello again!
Let's find out more about Maria's life.
As you recall,
Maria is an Operations and Logistics Manager
for a large producer of medical equipment
with distribution centers
in the United Kingdom and Europe.
Every morning,
Maria has a walk around the factory,
which is full of IoT technologies
that enable the correct performance
and delivery of all processes.
The first thing that Maria does is log
into the control panel of the operation center
to make sure that all of the machinery
and processes are performing correctly.
This is done automatically through
sensors that enable face recognition.
When she's logged in,
she notices there's a warning alarm
on the main screen
indicating that machine number 3
needs to be restarted as soon as possible
due to a malfunction in its operating system.
The system suggests restarting
the machine after 9:00 pm,
when production levels are low
and there's no interference with the workflow.
Using her corporate tablet,
Maria is able to decide whether to approve
the system's recommendation,
set up a new time or ignore the warning.
The second activity Maria does
is walk around the factory
talking to the different engineers
that work there.
A new alarm pops up on her tablet.
It's a red alarm!
Peter, the engineer,
approaches Maria, grabs her tablet
and, using a code,
remotely enables a cool-down drill.
The cooling system around machine number 2
starts to bring down
the engine's temperature automatically.
The factory is safe!
After this event,
Maria is able to keep walking around the factory.
Do you remember Maria's security helmet?
This helmet is also connected
to the factory system via IoT.
This type of equipment allows organizations
to provide safety measures
for all employees working
in risky environments.
Nevertheless, this is not magic,
as some accidents cannot be predicted
and as the common saying goes:
"accidents do happen!"
A new notification pops up in her tablet.
It says: "Use caution in aisle 4!"
Given this information,
Maria decides to avoid aisle 4,
and sends a report to the security department.
This is a normal day in Maria's daily routine
with IoT solutions
in the operations and logistics field.
How do you think IoT can affect other areas?