In the second section,
you're going to express
why you picked this company and position.
Now grab their attention
and tell them why you picked them.
Don't just start talking about yourself.
You will talk about yourself later on.
This is where most students go wrong.
This is your shot to make the hiring manager
or the company feel special
and let them know
that you are genuinely interested in them.
This will grab their attention
and get them interested in you.
You want to integrate emotion here
and show the hiring manager that you're not
just sending out a generic cover letter
where you highlight your skills.
Go the extra mile
and make them feel this is the only company
you want to work for.
Remember,
the rule of thumb here is if the recruiter
can cover the company's name
and substitute for another company's name,
that means you have written
a generic cover letter
and your candidacy might be discarded.
And try to refrain
from using trending buzzwords
or don't you say that they seem like
an exciting company to work for,
they can see right through that.
Here, you want to give them the real reason
as to why you think they're exciting.
So remember, you're answering
the question "why this company?"
It's important to customize
this section as much as possible.
Here are some ways to do just that.
Check out their articles on social media,
like LinkedIn, for example.
You can mention the success
of a recent transaction
or something that stands out to you
about the company business
and where it's heading.
You can indicate that you attended
an on campus or virtual online event
which the company hosted or participated in,
highlight one of their speakers
and something you found interesting
about what they said.
Next, read available information,
go on the company website,
learn their values and mission.
You can read their news pages
and use their company culture vocabulary
in your cover letter.
Has anything caught your attention
about their specific clients
or company strategies?
If so, use this approach and mention them.
Another alternative to customize
your cover letter is to ask yourself:
have you had a conversation with an alumni
or someone in your network working
at that company
that was meaningful to you?
Did they say anything about
the company that inspired you?
If so, mention how this inspired you to apply.
You can also research company directors
and see if you have anything in common:
which charities do they work with?
What type of volunteer work do they encourage
their employees to participate in?
Do you have something in common
with these company activities?
Here, you can use
an emotional attachment you have with them.
No matter what,
don't just say that they seem inspiring
because they've donated money
to their local charity for X amount of years.
Anyone can read the headlines of a website.
Pick something genuine that you can relate to
which will allow you to make that impact.
The idea is to show that you know
what differentiates their company
by having done your homework and research.
Remember,
this is what you find appealing
about this particular firm.