Hi everyone.
At IE Talent and Careers,
we understand the pain that you may feel
when applying to jobs.
That's why today we're going
to help you overcome some of this pain
by focusing on cover letters.
First of all, we recommend
you put as much focus and energy
into your cover letter as you do your CV.
A good cover letter
can make the biggest difference.
For example, if you're shortlisted for a position,
the hiring managers
will go through your cover letter
to make their final decision.
Before we begin, you need to have the following,
or else it's going to be
a dark and lonely place to get started.
First things first:
time.
Cover letters take time to write.
So, we recommend you dedicate
at least 90 solid minutes to this task.
Next, your CV should be ready and prepared
as if you were going to apply the same day.
Then, you need the job description
of the position you're applying to in front of you
and you need to know or have an idea
of what your competitive advantages are.
Now, what exactly is the cover letter?
A cover letter is a document
sent with your resume
to provide additional information
on your skills and experience.
This letter provides detailed information
on why you are qualified
for the job you're applying for.
So, you shouldn't simply repeat
what's on your resume,
rather include specific information
on why you're a strong match
for the employer's requirements.
Think of your cover letter as a sales pitch
that will market your credentials
and help you get that interview.
You want to make sure
your cover letter makes the best impression
on the person who's reviewing it.
Now you're thinking; "okay, great to know.
What do you include in a cover letter?"
Well, there are four sections in a cover letter,
which we will go through individually.
The first part is about you.
It's a self-introduction saying who you are
and the position you're applying to.
The second part is about them, the company,
explaining what you find appealing
about this particular company.
The third part is where you answer
the question "why me?"
What can you do for them that others can't?
Basically, what is your competitive advantage?
You can show this by giving examples
related to the job offer,
which you already have
in front of you as you write it.
And the fourth part is saying goodbye,
which is the closing
and how you would like to follow up.