In this stage, you have to show them
how much you want it.
Keep in mind the person reading
your cover letter doesn't know you.
So, if you can make an emotional connection,
all the better.
As a result, in your closing, you really need
to think about using the right words.
Instead of the typical
"thanks for your consideration"
or "looking forward to hearing from you",
you can say something along the lines of
"I look forward to meeting you
in the next interview phase".
If you know what the next interview phase is,
then name it specifically.
You need to use language
that you feel comfortable with,
but shows the company that you really want this.
In addition, if you decide
to say that you will follow up,
make sure you have their contact to do so.
Most importantly,
make sure you actually do follow up.
Remember,
we all want to work with people
who want to be part of our team
and your cover letter
is your chance to express just that.
Now, follow these steps
to write a winning cover letter
and let them know how much
you really want this position.
Good luck!