I want to talk to you
about the professional networking site
LinkedIn.
LinkedIn is a powerful tool
that you can use to establish
your professional online presence,
network with prospective employers,
clients and alumni from your school
and strategize your job search.
This also applies
if you want to start your own business
or freelance for different projects.
If you're not on LinkedIn
or you have a profile
but have not logged on for months,
pay close attention.
Here's why LinkedIn is a good idea.
First reason, it's be there or be square.
There are over 30 million companies
on LinkedIn and counting.
Bottom line is hiring managers
and even recruiters are there.
Even if you applied through their website,
there is a very good chance
that they will look you up online
and your LinkedIn profile
will be high at the top of the search.
Having a good profile with an active network
will help you build trust and credibility.
Second reason, networking 101.
With over 600 million members and counting,
LinkedIn is one of the biggest databases
of people in the world.
With this number of potential contacts,
who would want to miss out?
Building a good network will always pay off.
You never know who can provide you
with an important insight
or put in a good word of reference for a job.
The networking being done on LinkedIn,
the one that really thrives anyways,
is informational networking,
the kind that is driven by sharing
of content and professional opinion,
but not so much the one that asks
for job referrals from the get-go.
Also, since potential clients
and investors are there too,
networking will definitely help
if you're starting up a company
or even founding the next unicorn startup,
who knows!
What matters is that you're present,
interacting in this unique professional forum
and you can make it extensive to the real world.
Anyone you meet at an event or conference,
you can ask to be a connection
and keep in touch through LinkedIn.
This is common practice
and really helps to keep connections alive.
Just remember to add a message
to your connection request.
It will help the person place you
and follow up with you in the future.
Third reason, job search strategy made easy.
There are over 20 million open job listings
on LinkedIn at any given time.
You can search for jobs by geography,
by role, by company, by keyword,
you name it.
This abundance is fantastic
because it gives you the opportunity
to learn about your market.
You can identify trends,
like sought-after roles or growing companies,
or see how one role
varies from one company to another.
Understanding what is needed out there
will help you leverage your profile
and play in your strengths.