Just like I mentioned in the first section,
"Why using LinkedIn is a good idea?",
hiring managers, recruiters
and investors are all there.
Even if you applied through their website
or you connected with them through other means,
there is a very good chance
that they will look you up online.
Your LinkedIn profile will be high
at the top of the search in Google,
and having a good solid profile
will help you build trust and credibility.
This is also true
even if you're not actively looking for a job.
Headhunters in HR know
that some of the best professionals out there
are the ones that are not looking for a change.
They are already doing great work
and making a difference where they are,
and so they're even more appealing to them.
If you are one of those,
a good LinkedIn profile will guarantee
you can be found by recruiters
and get the call for an interesting job.
Then the decision will be yours
on whether to pursue it or not.
LinkedIn tells us that members
that have a complete profile
get 40 times more views than members
with an incomplete profile,
so it is always worth it
to invest your time on this.
But how exactly do you build
a good solid profile?
Let's find out.
There are eight main sections
in your LinkedIn profile worth thinking about.
We will go through each one
and tell you about a couple others extra.
You have the picture,
the headlines, the About section,
education, professional experience, skills,
recommendations and interests.
The first part,
an informative profile headline.
Regarding headline:
your headline is a short,
memorable professional slogan for yourself,
and it is also a declaration of intentions.
It is the perfect place to state
where you see yourself after graduating.
Look at these examples.
You have: MBA, digital transformation,
e-commerce, retail, banking, finance.
Another example:
B.A., international relations,
sustainability, technology, NGOs,
and MSE, international management,
consultant, driving digitalization
in retail and e-commerce.
These headlines look interesting, don't they?
It's because they are very targeted
to what their owners want.
Note how they have education,
role, and finally sector.
Search algorithms on LinkedIn
will pick up on these keywords
and make your profile pop up
for any headhunter or prospective employer
looking for such skills.
If you're not clear on what you want exactly,
that's okay.
Hunt for keywords in job postings
you would be interested in applying for.
So, don't just write "MBA candidate"
or "Master's in management candidate",
a prospective employer or headhunter
would never search for just that.
Craft your very own headline
and make your profile really stand out.
Pick your photos.
You get to have two photos
on your LinkedIn profile.
Make good use of this opportunity
to establish your professional brand.
There is your picture and the background image.
Your picture
should definitely be professional.
Wear a business or a business casual attire,
make sure there's a light
and neutral background,
and throw in a nice smile.
Avoid cutaways from group pictures,
or full-body pictures,
where your face will not be seen clearly.
The background image should resonate
with your professional goals.
This is a good chance to get creative,
give it a shot!
Try out a couple of images
and get feedback from your classmates
to double check if you're sending
the right message.
Develop a unique professional summary.
After defining your title
and picking your photos,
you will have noticed that LinkedIn
is a place to shine.
You get to show off your brand
and what you're all about.
So, in the professional summary,
try not to just copy and paste
from the professional summary in your CV.
You're more than just that.
Tell your story to connect
with a visitor of your profile
so they want to know more about you.
Go beyond typical buzzwords
such as "creative problem solver"
and "passion about technology and innovation".
That all sounds fine,
but the question is this:
why would you like to join this or that sector?
What kind of challenges
do you identify in the sector?
What kinds of problems do you like to solve?
Remember,
it's not about what you're looking for,
but what you can bring to a potential employer.
Ultimately,
prospective employers are interested
in how they can benefit
from connecting with you.
Include a link to your website,
if you have one, or any other media,
such as published articles
or interviews you were featured in,
to make your profile all the more engaging.
Show off your education.
List out your education,
including your current IE studies
and the most recent.
Include all your schools, summer programs
and complementary activities
you participated in,
like clubs or teams.
Don't be shy to show off your GPA scores,
only if they're outstanding though,
and honors.
It's perfectly appropriate to do so
and it might help a prospective employer
leans towards interviewing you
instead of someone else.
Showcase your professional experience.
Although your first instinct is to state
that you're currently not working,
that's not necessarily true.
Continuing education is hard work.
The idea is to avoid having
your current experience as unemployed.
The easiest solution
is to list out your IE degree
as your current position right now,
and make sure you list
the most relevant courses you are taking,
leadership positions,
or any other activities you are
or will be participating in.
If you're considering changing careers,
this is also a great place
to demonstrate what you're doing
during your studies to close the gap
between your previous career
and your aspired position.
Overall, the experience section
can help you showcase
all your past professional achievements
and projects,
and without the space constraint
you have in your CV.
Your profile can be as long as you want.
Just remember it should be reader-friendly
and have a clear structure.
Here's a tip:
use the first lines to explain
the type of company you worked for,
and any major accomplishments you had there.
Then you can move on to expand
on your experience within that company.
List out your skills and get endorsed for them.
This section is the place
to include keywords and phrases
that a recruiter will actually search for.
Find relevant ones in job listings
that appeal to you
and profiles of people
you have in your network
with the kinds of roles you want.
List all your possible keywords
in the relevant language
of the geography you're targeting
in their most common spelling.
For example, tech versus technology.
Other people on LinkedIn
will get the chance to endorse these skills.
However, the best endorsement
will come from the recommendation section
coming up now.
Collect diverse recommendations.
The best profiles
have at least one recommendation
for every position they have had.
Reach out to your peers,
your professors, a teammate
or an ex-manager for this.
You can make their life easier,
telling them specifically what you need
in terms of a skill or a project
you need endorsement for,
and if they would be comfortable
posting it on your LinkedIn profile.
You may reciprocate by providing
your own recommendations to them.
Overall, these recommendations
are nice to have,
but note that they will not substitute
official recommendations
if a company requires them
during the recruitment process.
Show your connectedness
by building the interest sections.
Groups you join will appear
at the bottom of your LinkedIn profile.
By joining groups, you will be more engaged
in the different professional communities
within LinkedIn.
Start by joining your university
and sector-related groups,
where you will be able
to foster solid relationships
with other professionals.
But we will see more about this
in the following section of this course.
Also, follow companies of your interest
and leaders that inspire you.
Other sections in your LinkedIn profile
are licenses and certifications,
accomplishments, volunteer experience.
It helps to have your profile
as complete as possible.
You will get 40 times more views
with a 100% complete profile
and you will give prospective employers
a better picture of who you are.